<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhian N. Kamvar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhian N. Kamvar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprint Day!</title>
      <link>/blog/preprint-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/preprint-day/</guid>
      <description>Today, we finally published a preprint for a manuscript that spans over 15 years of data 🎉!
Our massive Sclerotinia pop gen study out as preprint today @PeerJPreprints https://t.co/O85hUURi2s #AgriculturalScience #Genetics #Mycology
&amp;mdash; Sydney Everhart (@SydneyEverhart) October 3, 2017  Here’s the citation:
 Kamvar ZN, Amaradasa BS, Jhala R, McCoy S, Steadman JR, Everhart SE. (2017) Population structure and phenotypic variation of Sclerotinia sclerotiorum from dry bean in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholarly Publications</title>
      <link>/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Grünwald NJ, Everhart SE, Knaus BJ, Kamvar ZN. (2017) Best practices for population genetic analyses. Phytopathology 107:9 doi: 10.1094/PHYTO-12-16-0425-RVW
Jombart T, Archer F, Schliep K, Kamvar ZN, Harris R, Paradis E, Goudet J, Lapp H (2017). apex: phylogenetics with multiple genes. Molecular Ecology Resources. 17:1 19-26 doi: 10.1111&amp;frasl;1755-0998.12567
Kamvar ZN, López-Uribe MM, Coughlan S, Grünwald NJ, Lapp H, Manel S (2017). Developing educational resources for population genetics in R: an open and collaborative approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squishing a big bad bug</title>
      <link>/blog/squish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/squish/</guid>
      <description>As I was preparing to push a new version of poppr to CRAN , this tweet (appropriately) came across my feed:
Mistakes happen in science. What matters is what you do next. Anyone want to share a story of a mistake &amp;amp; how they handled it?
&amp;mdash; Adrienne Porter Felt (@__apf__) September 10, 2017  The reason I was updating poppr was to fix a mistake I had made a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a computational biologist currently working a post-doctoral researcher in the lab of Dr. Sydney E. Everhart at the Department of Plant Pathology at University of Nebraska-Lincoln. My research focus seeks to understand the mechanisms that drive the evolution of clonal plant pathogens.
I grew up in Cupertino, CA, but got my undergraduate degree in Biology at Truman State University in Kirksville, MO where I had a research opportunity to work on understanding the regulation of shoot apical meristem development in maize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20,000 downloads under the C(RAN)</title>
      <link>/blog/20-000-downloads-under-the-c-ran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/20-000-downloads-under-the-c-ran/</guid>
      <description>My R package poppr hit over 20,000 downloads on CRAN. I thought this would be a nice opportunity to briefly talk about what initiated the development. Before that, let’s look at the cumulative number of downloads:
CRAN you dig it? Thanks to the fantastic cranlogs package, assessing the download history of a package is quite simple (with the caveat that these are logs from the rstudio mirror, so the value is almost always lower than the true value).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating Figure 3</title>
      <link>/blog/recreating-figure-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/recreating-figure-3/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In February of 2016, I got an email asking if I could provide the code to recreate figure three from my article in Phytopathology on the outbreak of Phytophthora ramorum in Curry County OR from 2001 to 2014 (paywalled, but you can find a copy here).
While I have the code used for the analysis on github, it’s a lot of stuff to sort through, considering that it was my first foray in attempting a reproducible analysis, so for this post, I’m going to recreate it using current tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>