<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhian N. Kamvar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhian N. Kamvar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>20,000 downloads under the C(RAN)</title>
      <link>/2016/12/29/20-000-downloads-under-the-c-ran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/29/20-000-downloads-under-the-c-ran/</guid>
      <description>My R package poppr hit over 20,000 downloads on CRAN. I thought this would be a nice opportunity to briefly talk about what initiated the development. Before that, let’s look at the cumulative number of downloads:
CRAN you dig it? Thanks to the fantastic cranlogs package, assessing the download history of a package is quite simple (with the caveat that these are logs from the rstudio mirror, so the value is almost always lower than the true value).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is currently under construction
 Science I am currently a post-doctoral researcher in the lab of Sydney E. Everhart at the Department of Plant Pathology at University of Nebraska, Lincoln. My work focuses on using reproducible methods to understand the population genetics of clonal organisms.
My Ph. D. is from the Department of Botany and Plant Pathology at Oregon State University. My dissertation focuses on my development of computational tools for analyzing clonal populations in the R package poppr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating Figure 3</title>
      <link>/2016/02/10/recreating-figure-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/10/recreating-figure-3/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In February of 2016, I got an email asking if I could provide the code to recreate figure three from my article in Phytopathology on the outbreak of Phytophthora ramorum in Curry County OR from 2001 to 2014 (paywalled, but you can find a copy here).
While I have the code used for the analysis on github, it’s a lot of stuff to sort through, considering that it was my first foray in attempting a reproducible analysis, so for this post, I’m going to recreate it using current tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>