<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>command-line on Zhian N. Kamvar</title>
    <link>https://zkamvar.github.io/tags/command-line/</link>
    <description>Recent content in command-line on Zhian N. Kamvar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zkamvar.github.io/tags/command-line/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Learned About 2-Factor Authentication on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://zkamvar.github.io/blog/2fa-with-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkamvar.github.io/blog/2fa-with-github/</guid>
      <description>Since the end of 2018, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of a collaboration between RECON and MSF called the R4EPIs initiative where we are trying to integrate a more standardized workflow of R for field epidemiologists so that it can be more cost-effective (no license fees) and troubleshooting among epidemiologists can be more effective. We have a repository to host templates for automated situation reports at https://github.com/R4EPI/sitrep. When we created the GitHub organisation, we wanted to make sure that the code being submitted to the repository was genuinely authored by the person and didn&amp;rsquo;t contain malware from a hijacked account1, so we required 2-factor authentication for the R4EPI github organisation from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the ABySS</title>
      <link>https://zkamvar.github.io/blog/installing-the-abyss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkamvar.github.io/blog/installing-the-abyss/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I wanted to explore assembling 55 genomes of Sclerotinia sclerotiorum to check for structural rearrangements that could be caused by sub-lethal fungicide exposure. I figured the best way to do this was to assemble these genomes de novo as opposed to aligning them to a reference. This brought me to installing the ABySS de novo assembler on the HCC Tusker Cluster… and I can happily report, that after half a day of command line bullshittery1, I had ABySS up and running 👍.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>